SIVA SANKARAN M S (1) Featured

Programmer Analyst seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Unix Shell Scripting, PostgreSQL, Python, AWS, Git



Current Designation: Programmer Analyst Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Programmer Analyst, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, Unix Shell Scripting, PostgreSQL, Python, AWS, Git

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Focused engineer with 2+ years of experience and bachelor's degree in Information Technology, to demonstrate the capabilities utilizing the opportunity provided. Experience in managing good relationship between the internal teams and Client teams. Constantly worked towards achieving Customer Satisfaction through meeting their requirements, knowledge sharing via meetings and mails.

To become part of an organization that promotes learning and development, providing me the opportunity to enhance my knowledge, add value to the organization and explore new technologies.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd as Programmer Analyst

Dec 2017 to Till Date

Data Processor Tools Development

February 2019 - Present

Currently working on Development of Tools for Customer's Business Analysis products. The project involves retrieval of customer and business data from AWS S3, processing the data and preparing it for subsequent data analysis modules. Multiple tools and processes that were originally performed manually and using shell scripts were automated with the implementation in Python.

Python Implementation of tools

AWS S3 retrieval, Data Parser and Formatter.

Design and development.

Migration from manual execution to the automated tools.

Analysis of legacy shell scripts

Bug fixes maintenance and deployments to EC2 instances.

Unit and Integration Tests.

Environment: Python, AWS, Linux, Visual Studio Code, Git

March 2018 - February 2019

Customer Escalation team often required monitoring of log and event

data for monitoring certain events and conditions to trigger custom

notifications. The feature developed would connect to various servers

over SSH and retrieve event data periodically. Based on the filters

configured, listeners would be notified of the events.

Contribution:

Development of the feature in Python.

SSH Client, Rest API Client, JSON log parsers

Implementation of various filter conditions to support different configurations.

Bug fix and maintenance.

Troubleshoot various events and support Escalation teams with data.

Environment: Python, Linux, Visual Studio Code/PyCharm, Git

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Sri cHANDRASEKHARENDRA SARASWATHI VISWA MAHA VIDYALAYA, **KANCHIPURAM** in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

AWS Certified Developer Associate

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Python, Java, AWS, Django			
Unix Shell Script, Git, BitBucket			
PostgreSQL, Agile Methodology			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time